Robert Hupka Collection of Toscanini Test Pressings and Dom Baron Chant Recordings
Robert Hupka Collection of Toscanini Test Pressings
1902-2006
1944-1964
Hupka, Robert.
90 linear ft.
Robert Hupka was a recording engineer for RCA and Columbia Records, and worked closely with noted conductor Arturo Toscanini for many years. Collection contains test pressings of various Toscanini performances, including rehearsals and a small amount of memorabilia relating to Toscanini, recordings of Gregorian chants, and assorted other classical secular and sacred music.
3283025
Biographical History
Arturo Toscanini (1867-1957) was an Italian conductor, renowned for his intensity and perfectionism. He is widely regarded as one of the greatest conductors of the 20th century.
Dom Ludovic Baron, O.S.B. is a Benedictine monk and music scholar with expertise in monastic chant. He is featured on at least one album, "Gregorian Chant by Dom Ludovic Baron, O.S.B." released by the Smithsonian Institution on their Folkways label, which includes an interview and explanation of chants.
Robert Hupka (1919-2001) was a Viennese-born recording engineer and photographer. He was a sound engineer for RCA and later for Columbia records, and worked closely with Toscanini for many years. A talented photographer, he also took thousands of photographs of the conductor which were published in 1963 in his book This Was Toscanini. Hupka's connection to Baron's chant recordings is unknown.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Robert Hupka Collection of Toscanini Test Pressings and Dom Baron Chant Recordings consists of a small amount of papers and a very large number of recordings.
Papers contain clippings, price guides, Toscanini's copy of Aida with his signature, material from the 1937 Salzburg Festival, two notes in Toscanini's hand, and some miscellaneous printed material (programs, etc.)
The 172 Dom Baron recordings, all on tape, span 1954-1957 and include masses, hymns, and Christmas and Easter special performances.
The 3608 Toscanini recordings, a mix of tape and disc, include test pressings of concerts, operas, festival performances, rehearsals, sacred music and more; for many of these, the location and date of the recording is given and in some cases additional information such as names of performers.
There are also 410 Miscellaneous recordings, which cannot be identified definitively as either Toscanini or Baron, or whose contents are entirely unknown. These recordings contain instrumental and vocal performances of secular and sacred pieces from classical composers (e.g. Beethoven, Bach) as well as modern ones (e.g. Benjamin Britten).
Arrangement of the Collection
Items are physically arranged in numerical order using Hupka's original numbering scheme up to Hupka 0747. There is then a gap in the numbering. Numbers beginning with Hupka 0800 were assigned by, for consistency. In the inventory below, items are subdivided by topic (Baron, Toscanini, Miscellaneous) and within that listed alphabetically by title. The miscellaneous recordings are subdivided by type and then listed alphabetically by title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Baron, Ludovic, 1894-; Hupka, Robert.; Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957.; Choral music.; Conductors (Music); Gregorian chants.; Instrumental music.; Sacred music.; Long-playing records.; Audiotapes.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Phonograph records.; Scores.; Sound recordings.; Souvenir programs.; Conductors.; Singers.; Sound engineers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to the tapes requires advance notice for production of a listening copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert Hupka, 2000.
Inventory
- Papers
  - Clippings, Apr 1949 (Box 1)
  - Original inventory, by Hupka (Box 1)
  - Price guides, catalogs, etc. (Box 1)
  - Salzburg Festival, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Toscanini correspondence, notes, 2 notes, signed (Box 1)
  - Toscanini's copy of Aïda, signed, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Toscanini miscellany, 1966; 1978,; 2006; programs, brochures, etc. (Box 1)
- Baron recordings
  - Ascension, hupka_0449; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    Alleluia - organ, birds (beauty); Credo; Offertory, Ascendit, Sanctus; O Salutoris, Agnus; Octave Day, conducted by D. B.; Vespers, Saturday after Ascension; Vidi Aquam, Sun with och of Ascension, Deus in adj., Terce (beautiful)
  - Bishop Fulton Sheen, hupka_0455; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
  - The Catholic Hour Program No. 1: Music in Catholic Workshop (Reel 1 of 4), 7/24/1957; hupka_0503; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    Gregorian chants
  - The Catholic Hour Program No. 2: Music in Catholic Workshop (Reel 2 of 4), 7/24/1957; hupka_0504; There is a note under "The Catholic Hour" that reads: "September 1957". Also there is an audio engineer note in the record's box.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    1 - Gregorian chant Lesson (Dom Baron); 2 - Gregorian chant Lesson (Margaret Leddy); 3 - Gregorian chant Lesson (Peggy)
  - Community - Reel 1, Side 1, hupka_0453; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    Community - Reel 1, Side 1
  - Concert, 5/6/1952; hupka_0270; Kyrie, Salve Regina, Regina Coeli, Alma Mater, Talk on Art, St. Elizabeth mass, ? Transfiguration, Lazarus, Prodigal Son, St. Stephen; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2)
  - Dom Baron, 8/28/1955; hupka_0499; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
  - Dom Baron Schola - Reel 2, hupka_0456; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    Note in the box reads: "Bad quality, fading
  - Dom Baron singing, hupka_0532A; Note reads: "too low speed"; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
    Kyries, Salve Regina, Alma Mater, etc.
  - Dom Baron with Mass Schola - talk, hupka_0452; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    Dom Baron with Mass Schola - talk
  - Dom Baron, Afternoon, 7/18/1956; 7/19/1956; hupka_0399; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 18): Discussion and comments on the Evangelical "Sacrae Musical Discipline", Communion of Christmas Mass. Vernacular; 2. Afternoon (July 19): Christmas, "Cantique d'Noel", 3rd Mass sung by Dom Baron in French
  - Dom Baron, Morning, 7/17/1956; 7/18/1956; hupka_0386; Trip to Scranton, PA; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Morning (July 17): Mass "Justus et Palma", Compline, Ave Verum - Mr. Marier, Trip to Scranton - Dom Baron; 2. Morning (July 18): Mass "Justus et Palma", Gradual mass, Alleluia, Offertory, Communion. Organ - Mr. Antor playing his organ sonata
  - Dom Baron, Reel 1, hupka_0458; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
  - Dom Baron, Reel 1, 8/28/1955; hupka_0502; This must be reel 1, not 2; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
  - Dom Baron, Reel 2, 8/28/1955; hupka_0501; This must be reel 2, not 1; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 6)
  - Dom Baron, Special: Morning, 7/2/1957; hupka_0407; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Morning: Opening Session
  - Dom Baron, TV (High) Mass, Reel 1, 8/28/1955; hupka_0430; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
  - Dom Baron, TV (High) Mass, Reel 2, 8/28/1955; hupka_0431; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/9/1954; hupka_0328; 1 side only. A side blank; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2)
    1. Blank; 2. Afternoon
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/28/1954; 7/29/1954; hupka_0342; Additional note on the index card reads: "28 & 29 afternoon (29th 1202 & 970) Sacred H. St. (illegible)"; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2)
    1. Afternoon (July 28); 2. Afternoon (July 29): Sacred Heart
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 8/2/1954; 8/3/1954; hupka_0346; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2)
    1. Afternoon (August 2): Magnificent St. Stephen's; Talk on art 414-18; 2. Afternoon (August 3): 1263, 1268, 375, 76, 79, 82, 384, 85, Our Lady
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 8/4/1954; 8/5/1954; hupka_0348; Note with the index card has illegible words.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2)
    1. Afternoon (August 4): Gloria patri, Vespers of Wednesday, Monastic not in books, 20th Sunday of Pentecost, 1063, 15-16, 317,318, 326, 323, 324, 327, 338, 340, 344, 47, 48, 49; 2. Afternoon (August 5): 337 Benedixiti; 352 Exulta, Elevare Monastic book, Annunciation Monastic book, 359 Vigil Christmas, 362 Offertory, Christmas 364,5 Kyrie, Baby little girl, 371, 392, 393, 5, 396, 399, 408, 1167, 430, Animae
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 8/10/1954; 8/11/1954; hupka_0351; Note with the index card has illegible words.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2)
    1. Reel No. 27-A: Afternoon (August 10): Passion time and Easter, Lazarus (not in book), Prodigal son 1088.551, O vos omnes 727, 480 Jubilate/ 756; 2. Reel No. 27-B: Afternoon (August 11): 780, 275, 792 Venite (not in book)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/6/1955; 7/9/1955; hupka_0366; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 6); 2. Afternoon (July 9): Beginning of the lectures on the Liturgical Season cont., Advent p. 327, Ant. 7a
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/7/1955; 7/8/1955; hupka_0367; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 7); 2. Afternoon (July 8): Beginning of classes on the Liturgical seasons, Advent, p. 319 1st Sunday of Advent
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/11/1955; 7/12/1955; hupka_0368; There are some comments on the index cards after 1864 Another "Rorate": "good example of rhythming syllic chant", and after 362 Offertory: ""When we make the liturgy there is something in heaven too because our Lord is not a statue"; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 11): Advent Cont.: p. 273, 277 Alma, 355 Qui Sedes Gradual, 3rd Sunday of Advent, 337 Offertory and Communion, 388 2 Antiphon 7b, 340 O Sapientia, 347 Exita, 348 Benedictus; 2. Afternoon (July 12): Definition of singing by St. Thomas "Exultatio mentis": p.532 Exulta, 353 4th Sunday of Advent "Rorate", 1864 Another "Rorate", 358 Antiphon 8 G at Prime, 359 Responsory & Introit, 362 Offertory - Christmas Eve, 363 Ant. 4A & 8C, 1082 Vox clamantis, 1083 Ecce mitto
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/13/1955; 7/14/1955; hupka_0369; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 13): p. 365 Hymn 1 of Christmas, 368 Invitatory, 371 1st Nocturn, 1 Ant., 372 2 Ant. 8G, 373 3 Ant., 375 Hodie nobis, 381 Lesson IV of Xmas, 721 "Anipet", 377 Quem Vidistis, 379 "Afferentur", 380 Antiphonary English, 382 O Magnum, 384 Sancta et immaculata nocturne, 388 3 Ant. 6F; 2. Afternoon (July 14): p. 360 Christmas Gradual, 392 Introit (interpret text as composer intended), 392 Gradual, 394 Offertory, 395 Communion, 1 Antiphon 2D
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/15/1955; 7/18/1955; hupka_0370; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 15): p. 396 Genuit puerpera, 397 Angelus, 399 Parvulus, 408 Puer, 409 Alleluia, 411 Notum, 412 Tecum, 418 Video (Solesmes recordings of Christmas Vespers Magnificat), Salve 276; 2. Afternoon (July 18): p. 442 O admirabile, 444 Ecce, 459 Epiphany: Gradual (on Solesmes records), 461 Offertory (note development over Tharsis like laque us, p. 430), 480 Jubilate octave of Epiphany, 486 Jubilate of 2nd Sunday after Epiphany (Solesmes old records), 481 Fili quid fecisti nobis sic? (Beginning of Public Life), 487 Dicit Dominus
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/19/1955; 7/20/1955; hupka_0371; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 19); 2. Afternoon (July 20): p. 504 Exsurge, 506 Sciant…Deus meus, 511 Est mihi, 514 Benedictus es, 516 Stans, 521 Exulti nas, 519 Immense, 519 Rerum, 518 Miserere
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/21/1955; 7/22/1955; hupka_0372; Note after Beginning of Lent: reads: "There is an artist's Requiem Mass in France on Ash Wednesday". Note after Discussion of intellectual ictus reads: "You should almost always hear the ictus, though sometimes more and sometimes hardly at all. When notes are close together, e.g. in a descending series of climaci, you hardly hear it and you might then call it intellectual". After Antiphons for Benediction: "some suggestions for variety"; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 21): Beginning of Lent: p. 521 Ant. 7, 524 Attende Domine, 526 Gradual, 528 Adjuva nos & Offertory: Exaltabo te (Assumption Offertory taken from this), 539 Audi, benigne; 2. Afternoon (July 22): Comparison of this morning' s singing with last year. Discussion of intellecutal ictus, Antiphons for Benediction, 1084 Vespers 1st week of Lent, 1086 Omnes autem, 1765 Subvenite comp. with monastic (the monastic is more prayerful)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/25/1955; 7/26/1955; hupka_0373; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 25): Instruction on singing litanio and Pange Lingua Tantum Ergo in processions, p. 1359 Adorna, Cistercian Antiphon of David and Absolom (8th Sun. after Pentecost) compared with Roman "Montes" p. 986; 2. Afternoon (July 26): page 1088 Vadam ad patrem meum, 551 Dixit autem Pater, Benedictine antiphon before the 3rd Sun. of Lent, 1088 "Malos male perdet" & another "Malos..." (not in our libers), 558 Nemo te condemnavit, 1095 Ille homo, 1096 Lazarus, 1096 Domine si hic fuisses
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/27/1955; 7/28/1955; hupka_0374; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 27): Record of Stanbroock Benedictine nums, Record of Magnificat by French Trappists, Record of French Benedictus nuns singing ceremony of taking the veil, p. 1340 3 Ant. "Annulo" (this is used at ceremony of taking the veil), p. 600 Offertory of Palm Sunday, 601 Communion of Palm Sunday, 573 Hoc corpus, 579 Rep. 2 "Collegerunt"; 2. Afternoon (July 28): p 583 Pueri Hebraeorum, 588 Gloria, laus, 579 Collegerunt (on Solesmes records), 219 Eripe me (Dom Baron - from officium Majoris Hebdomadae et octave Paschae), Custodi me (Holy Thurs. record), Adversum me (Dom Baron), 653 Christus factus est, 680 Tenebrae, 681 Animam meam, 727 O vos omnes, p. 737 (compared with same on)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/29/1955; 8/1/1955; hupka_0375; Note after Popule meus reads: "prob. From Gollican liturgy, same who wrote "Veni Sancte Spiritus"; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 29): Popule meus, 708 Crucem tuam, 575 Vexilla Regis (Solesmes monks), 778 Resurrexi (quiet joy), Haec dies (Joy of Church, same as Gradual & Dead), 779 Alleluia, 780 Victimae, 781 Pascha nostrum, 792 Venite, 795 Portas, Ant. Of St. Mary Magdalen from Benedictine Liber., 800 Ant 7B Tulerunt; 2. Afternoon (August 1): 806 Benedictus - Off., Saturday in Easter week, 808 Nunc sancte Hymn 8, 809 Quasimodo, Alleluia, 811 Mitte, 812 Ad regias Hymn 8, 820 Modicum, 821 Jubilate, 822 Alleluia 4, 825 Vado, 826 Cantate, 829 Vado, 833 Cantate, 834 Petite (modern French hymn, probably adapted from the chant)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 8/2/1955; 8/3/1955; hupka_0376; Note reads: "There are no problems only solutions"; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (August 2): 853 lie derelinguas nos orpharos, Kyrie IX pressus oriscus p. XI, 81 Kyrie, 854 Exandi Domine, 856 Alleluia - Nos vos nel, 862 Non vas relinguam, 889 Spiritus sanctus, 892 Spiritus, 989 Alleluia - O quam bonns, 916 Te Deum, 960 Puer Samnel, 963 Domine convertere, Cantabo Domino, 964 Exi cito; 2. Afternoon (August 3): Discussion on Gregorian chant in Vernacular, Procession for Liturgical Play
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 8/4/1955; 8/5/1955; hupka_0377; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (August 4): Vespers in chapel St. Dominic; 2. Afternoon (August 5): p. 1014 Alleluia, 1016 A Magnif. Ant 4E, 1019 Qui manducat, Scriptum est enim, 1027 Bene omnia fecit, 1030 Precatus est, 1035 In speravi, 1074 Dicit Dominus, 1076 De profundo, Gradual & Off. 1077 Ant 1F
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 8/8/1955; 8/9/1955; hupka_0378; Additional note on the index card reads: "Liturgy com go without Gregorian Chant, but G. C. helps … very food 1768; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (August 8): Records of Assumption Mass: 1755 Audi filia, new and original Offertory 528, 1633 Stabat sancta Maria, 1634 Stabat mater; 2. Afternoon (August 9): Comments on Drama, 1120 Sancti tui, 1802 Nocturns, 1803 Comments on St. Thomas More Society evening talk
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/3/1956; 7/5/1956; hupka_0394; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 3): 1st Sunday of Advent, Introit p. 318, Gradual p. 320, Tape of Benedictine Nuns; 2. Afternoon (July 5): 1st Sunday of Advent, Alleluia & Verse, Offertory, Communion
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/6/1956; 7/7/1956; hupka_0395; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 6): 1st Sun. of Advent, Vepsers, 2nd Sun. of Advent, Introit, Gradual; 2. Afternoon (July 7): 2nd Sun. of Advent p. 329, Lactatus sum p. 330, Offertory, Communion, Ecce apparebit 332, Ecce in unbibus 331, Urbs 332, Ecce dominus 333, Tues qui venturus es 333, 1080 Expectabo
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/9/1956; 7/10/1956; hupka_0396; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 9): Antiphons for Advent p. 1083-4, 3rd Sun. of Advent, Introit, Gradual, Alleluia; 2. Afternoon (July 10): 3rd Sun. of Advent, Offertory, Communion, Vespers, O Antiphons
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/11/1956; 7/12/1956; hupka_0397; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 11): O Antiphons, Sat. in Easter week of Advent, 4th Sun. of Advent; 2. Afternoon (July 12): Hymn Benedictus (Sat. of Easter week of Advent), Christmas Eve, Christmas, I Vespers, Matius (recording of Dom Baron)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/13/1956; 7/17/1956; hupka_0398; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3)
    1. Afternoon (July 13): Christmas; 2. Afternoon (July 17): Christmas, interesting points about the Offertory
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/20/1956; 7/23/1956; hupka_0400; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 20): Christmas II Vesp., Recordings of French nuns taught by Dom Ludovic Baron; 2. Afternoon (July 23): Christmas - 3rd Mass, Alleluia, Offertory, Communion, St. Stephen
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/24/1956; 7/25/1956; hupka_0401; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 24): Mass of St. Stephen Cont., Communion, Nuptial Mass, St. John; 2. Afternoon (July 25): Holy Innocents
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/27/1956; 7/30/1956; hupka_0402; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 27): Discussion on vernacular and congregational singing; 2. Afternoon (July 30): Mass for Sun. after Christmas
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/31/1956; 8/1/1956; hupka_0403; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 31): Sunday within oct. of Christmas, circumcision; 2. Afternoon (August 1): Circumcision, Holy Name
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 8/6/1956; 8/7/1956; hupka_0404; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (August 6): Consecration of Virgins; 2. Afternoon (August 7): Consecration of Virgins (cont.)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 8/8/1956; hupka_0405; Additional note on the index card reads: "How can we find a melody of god speaking to the secret?; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon: Chapel Solemn Benediction, Dom Ludovic Baron, O.S.B. conducting chant, Ted Marier conducting Polyphony; 2. Afternoon: "Sisters of French Institute" from Fordham visiting. Mass of the Assumption comparisons with Christmas, 528, 470 Holy Family, 1709 Christ King, 778 Easter Sunday (NY Times), 590 Palm Sunday, 779 Pascha, Last Class
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/2/1957; 7/3/1957; hupka_0421; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 2); 2. Afternoon (July 3)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/5/1957; 7/6/1957; hupka_0422; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 5): Forth Sun. after Pentecost, Gradual, Offertory, Communion; 2. Afternoon (July 6): Mass XI, 4th Sun. after Pentecost, David - Jonatas, Montes Gelboe
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/8/1957; 7/9/1957; hupka_0423; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 8): 5th Sun. after Pentecost: Alleluia, Introit, Communion; 2. Afternoon (July 9): Divine prayers (DB), Jubilate
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/10/1957; 7/11/1957; hupka_0424; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 10): 6th Sun. after Pentecost, Our Lady of Mount Carmel; 2. Afternoon (July 11): Thursday Compline, 5th Sun. after Pentecost: Introit, Gradual, Alleluia
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/12/1957; 7/15/1957; hupka_0425; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 12); 2. Afternoon (July 15)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/16/1957; 7/17/1957; hupka_0426; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 16): Big discussion for what to sing for the radio; 2. Afternoon (July 17)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/9/1957; 7/10/1957; 7/16/1957; 7/17/1957; hupka_0427; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 9 & 10): Compline; 2. Afternoon (July 16 & 17): Compline - Feast of Our Lady of Mount Carmel, Great Slave
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/18/1957; 7/19/1957; hupka_0428; Note on the back of the index card reads: "Cardinal Spellman visit Manhattanville college this PM".; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 18); 2. Afternoon (July 19): Sexagesima Sunday. Offertory pg. 508 (interpretation of music and text. Main idea: Hope in God's guidance, pg. 778 Easter Introit, Communion pg. 1009, 6th Sun. after Pentecost, pg. 1103- Anr., pg.1009- Anr.)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/22/1957; 7/23/1957; hupka_0429; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 22): Hymn, pg. 1211 Jesu Corona Virginum, pg. 1666 Custodes, pg. 237 Inclina, Sub Venite 1265; 2. Afternoon (July 23): Pg. 1216, pg. 1323, pg. 1338 St. Agnes
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/25/1957; 7/29/1957; hupka_0429A; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (July 25): Mass for St. Ann, pg. 83 Kyrie VI, Mass for 7th Sun. after Pentecost; 2. Afternoon (July 29): Introit pg. 1574 (compared with pg. 616), Communion pg. 1576 (compared with 1st Sunday of Advent), pg. 1201, pg. 1202, pg. 1603
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/30/1957; 8/1/1957; hupka_0483; Note reads: "July 31st, '57 - No afternoon class, because of recording of polyphony"; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    1. No Afternoon (July 30); 2. Afternoon (August 1): Men Pq. 103-31 - Dialogue between Moses & God, Women Pq. 48, For concert Aug. 4
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 5/18/1957; 8/2/1957; hupka_0484; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    1. Afternoon (May 18): Dom Ludovic Baron, O.S.B. to minor seminary - St. Meinrad (copy of Father Ambrose's tape); 2. Afternoon (August 2): Rehearsal for Concert
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 7/5/1957; 8/6/1957; hupka_0485; Note over the July 5 side reads: "One side ONLY"; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    1. Afternoon (July 5): Benediction in chapel (all women, only 2 or 3 men. Not the best); 2. Afternoon (August 6): 2nd Vespers of the Feast of the Transfiguration (Prom Room)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, 5/19/1957; 8/7/1957; 9/3/1957; hupka_0486; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    1. Afternoon (May 19): Talk to Friends, St. Meinrad; 2. Afternoon (August 7): Mass of St. Pius X in practice (Sept. 3); The story of Father Baromb[?] books (how he made his books)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, Mechanic's Building, Newton, Boston, 8/29/1956; hupka_0446; Index card present in the tape box. Note reads: "Some good soul. To continue paly the other side of this reel. These 45 records were accidentally erased by some good soul who wanted to listen, but had to press the key that says RECORD. Then there was great amazement that no sound came out of the tape."; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    1. Afternoon, Mechanic's Building, Boston: Convention of Teachers' Institute
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, Newton, 8/13/1956; 8/14/1956; hupka_0435; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4)
    1. Afternoon (August 13): Mon. Req.; 2. Afternoon (August 14)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, Newton, 8/16/1956; 8/17/1956; hupka_0436; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    1. Afternoon (August 16); 2. Afternoon (August 17)
  - Dom Baron: Afternoon, Newton, 8/21/1956; 8/23/1956; hupka_0438; Notes read: "Aug. 21: Noting on this tape of the 21st session. Must be run off after tape emptied. Aug. 23 Dom Baron did not take class on 22nd.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 5)
    1. Afternoon (August 21); 2. Afternoon (August 23)